const e="english",o=200,a=40,t=[{id:1214,question:"He maintained that Nigerians need a leader with an <u>iron fist</u>",option:{a:" fist made of iron",b:"severe in treatment",c:" difiicult to please",d:"strong as iron"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Iron fist is used in reference to the exercise of power in an oppressive or ruthless way. A particularly severe, forceful, and uncompromising manner of ruling/governing.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:21,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1215,question:"The emphasis placed on good moral conduct by the society in the past seems to have been <u>relaxed</u>",option:{a:"avoided",b:"improved",c:"weakened",d:"outdated"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"relax: make or become less tense or anxious.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:22,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1216,question:"The matter was considered a <u>private</u> concern of the chairman to handle",option:{a:"personal",b:"known",c:"public",d:"open"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Private: belonging to or for the use of one particular person or group of people only.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:23,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1217,question:"He was underrated at the <u>preliminary</u> stage of the competition",option:{a:"advance",b:"initial",c:"selection",d:"crucial"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Preliminary: preceding or done in preparation for something fuller or more important.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:24,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1218,question:"The office assistant was dismissed for <u>pilfering</u>",option:{a:"fighting",b:"incompetence",c:"stealing",d:"mismanagement"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"PIlfering: steal (things of little value).",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:25,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1219,question:"Almost everyone she had worked with took advantage of her <u>meekness</u>",option:{a:"gentleness",b:"weakness",c:"steadfastness",d:"generosity"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Meekness: the fact or condition of being meek; submissiveness.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:26,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1220,question:"Barely six months after his father's demise, he has nothing left again of his <u>patrimony</u>",option:{a:"inheritance",b:"property",c:"reputation",d:"valuables"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Patrimony: property inherited from one's father or male ancestor. Also, valued things passed down from previous generations.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:27,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1221,question:`choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.

His grandfather was one of the few <u>patriotic</u> Nigerians who ever lived.`,option:{a:"obedient",b:"lover of Nigeria",c:"calculative",d:"careless"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Patriotic: having or expressing devotion to and vigorous support for one's country. It also implies showing love for your country and being proud of it",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:28,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1222,question:"Many people believed that such an action is <u>unbecoming</u> of a leader",option:{a:"forthcoming",b:". not befitting",c:"unwanted",d:" not necessary"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Unbecoming: (of behaviour) not fitting or appropriate; unseemly.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:29,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1223,question:"The governor was <u>incoherent</u> in his speech",option:{a:"uncoordinated",b:"talkative",c:"confused",d:"eloquent"},section:"choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Incoherent: (of spoken or written language) expressed in an incomprehensible or confusing way; unclear.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:30,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1224,question:"The lady has devised a means of <u>tackling</u> her current challenges.",option:{a:"attacking",b:"avoiding",c:"handling",d:"suspending"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`Tackling: make determined efforts to deal with (a problem or difficult task).

Avoiding: keep away from or stop oneself from doing (something).`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:31,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1225,question:"One hundred and forty kilometres per hour is a <u>reasonable</u> speed limit. ",option:{a:"acceptable",b:"unbelievable",c:"outrageous",d:"detestable"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`Reasonable:as much as is appropriate or fair; moderate.

Outrageous: shockingly bad or excessive.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:32,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1226,question:"The annual festival attracts <u>dignitaries</u> from both home and abroad.",option:{a:"spectators",b:"celebrities",c:"chieftains",d:"nonentities"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"d",solution:`Dignitary: a person considered to be important because of high rank or office.

nonentity: a person or thing with no special or interesting qualities; an unimportant person or thing.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:33,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1227,question:"The soldiers were <u>remorseful</u> for their inhuman treatment of the civilians.",option:{a:"boastful",b:"sad",c:"successful",d:"reliable"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Remorseful: filled with remorse; sorry.

Boastful: showing excessive pride and self-satisfaction in one's achievements, possessions, or abilities.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:34,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1228,question:"nsecurity has <u>escalated</u> since the present government came into power.",option:{a:"abated",b:"increased",c:"proliferated",d:"metamorphosed"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Escalate: increase rapidly.

Abate: (of something unpleasant or severe) become less intense or widespread`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:35,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1229,question:"It is <u>embarrassing</u> to accept our mistakes and tender an apology.",option:{a:"acceptable",b:"honourable",c:"detestable",d:"pardonable"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`Embarrassing: causing embarrassment.

Honourable: bringing or deserving honour.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:36,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1230,question:"The lawmakers are perceived to be the <u>greediest</u> set of politicians.",option:{a:"selfless",b:"unwanted",c:"popular",d:"corrupt"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Greedy: Having or showing a strong or excessive desire to acquire money or possess things,

Selfless: concerned more with the needs and wishes of others than with one's own; unselfish.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:37,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1231,question:"James found the photocopied material <u>invaluable</u> while preparing for the examination ",option:{a:"Valuable",b:"worthwhile",c:"worthless",d:"important"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`Invaluable: extremely useful; indispensable.

worthless: having no real value or use.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:38,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1232,question:"Mr. Akin's health has greatly <u>degenerated</u> in the last week.",option:{a:"improved",b:"deteriorated",c:"expanded",d:"abated"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Degenerated: decline or deteriorate physically, mentally, or morally.

improved: having become or been made better.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:39,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1233,question:"The incumbent president <u>conceded</u> defeat before the final result was announced.",option:{a:"accepted",b:"rejected",c:"opposed",d:"challenged"},section:"choose the option nearly opposite in meaning to the word(s) underlined",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`Concede: admit or agree that something is true after first denying or resisting it.

Reject: refuse to agree to (a request).`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:40,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1234,question:"choose the option with the correct spelling from the options lettered A-E",option:{a:"Interprete",b:"Interpret",c:"Inteprete",d:"Interprette"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:41,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1235,question:"choose the option with the correct spelling from the options lettered A-E",option:{a:"Sucesful",b:"Succeful",c:"Successful",d:"Sucessful"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:42,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1236,question:"choose the option with the correct spelling from the options lettered A-E",option:{a:"Acommodation",b:"Accomodation",c:"Accormodation",d:"Accommodation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:43,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1237,question:"Biography ",option:{a:"bioGRAphy",b:"BIography",c:"biograPHY",d:"biOgraphy"},section:`choose the option with the correct emphatic stress indicated in capital letters from the options lettered A-D
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:`Stress usually falls on the syllable before the group of letters 'graphy', tion, ogy, ify, ical, etc.

bi-O-gra-phy.
The syllable before 'graphy' in the word 'biology' is 'O'`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:44,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1238,question:"Successful",option:{a:"SUccessful",b:"suCcessful",c:"sucCEssful",d:"succESSful"},section:`choose the option with the correct emphatic stress indicated in capital letters from the options lettered A-D
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:45,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1239,question:"Democracy",option:{a:"DEmocracy",b:"deMOcracy",c:"demoCRAcy",d:"democraCY"},section:`choose the option with the correct emphatic stress indicated in capital letters from the options lettered A-D
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:46,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1240,question:"Conventional",option:{a:"conVENtional",b:"CONventional",c:"convenTIOnal",d:"conventioNAL"},section:`choose the option with the correct emphatic stress indicated in capital letters from the options lettered A-D
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:47,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1241,question:"The two friends made promises to _____ when they met last year",option:{a:" each other",b:"one another",c:"theirselves",d:"themselves"},section:"complete the statement from the options lettered A-D",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:48,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1242,question:"The meeting was organised at _______ instance ?",option:{a:"whom",b:"whose's",c:"whose",d:"whom's"},section:"complete the statement from the options lettered A-D",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Whose is the possessive form of the pronoun 'who'",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:49,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1243,question:"Mr. Jude made the meeting _____his poor health",option:{a:"even though",b:" inspite of",c:" in spite of",d:" despite that"},section:"complete the statement from the options lettered A-D",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:50,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1244,question:"The manager met the ______ who came visiting last week ",option:{a:"dark tall good-looking American",b:"good-looking tall dark American",c:"Tall dark American good-looking",d:"American dark tall good-looking"},section:"complete the statement from the options lettered A-D",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`Order of adjectives formula; quantity, opinion, size, age, colour, shape, origin, material or purpose.

good-looking(opinion)

Tall (size)

dark (colour) 

American (origin)`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:51,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1245,question:"H<u>ea</u>d",option:{a:"bead",b:"red",c:"rear",d:"stir"},section:"choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the letter(s) underlined from the options lettered A-E",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:52,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1246,question:"M<u>oo</u>n",option:{a:"cook",b:"loop",c:"pull",d:"look"},section:"choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the letter(s) underlined from the options lettered A-E",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:53,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1247,question:" Cr<u>ee</u>p",option:{a:"beep",b:"bring",c:"tread",d:"credit"},section:"choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the letter(s) underlined from the options lettered A-E",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:54,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1248,question:"<u>K</u>ing",option:{a:"that",b:"think",c:"thine",d:"tongue"},section:"choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the letter(s) underlined from the options lettered A-E",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:55,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1249,question:"<u>T</u>each",option:{a:"deviate",b:"through",c:"wrath",d:"both"},section:"choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the letter(s) underlined from the options lettered A-E",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:56,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1250,question:"<u>B</u>ark",option:{a:"climb",b:"tomb",c:"curb",d:"doubt"},section:"choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the letter(s) underlined from the options lettered A-E",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:57,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1251,question:"The Parents Teachers Association promised to build a CAFETERIA. ",option:{a:"Does the alumni association promised to build a cafeteria?",b:"Does the school authority promised to build a library?",c:"Did the parents teachers association promise to build a library?",d:"Does the parents teachers association promised to demolish a cafeteria?"},section:"choose the option that best answers the question from the options lettered A-D",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`Option C is the correct answer because CAFETERIA contradicts the word 'library'. The interrogative statement, therefore, provides a chance to emphasize the word CAFETERIA.

Did the parents teachers association promise to build a library? No, The Parents Teachers Association promised to build a CAFETERIA. `,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:58,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1252,question:"He SLAPPED the teacher.",option:{a:"Did he greet the teacher?",b:"Did the teacher flog him?",c:"Did he slap the nurse?",d:" Did he praise the principal?"},section:"choose the option that best answers the question from the options lettered A-D",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Option A is the correct answer because SLAPPED contradicts the word 'greet'. The interrogative statement, therefore, provides a chance to emphasize the word slapped.

Did he greet the teacher? NO, he slapped the teacher.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:59,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1253,question:"He travels every WEEKEND",option:{a:" Does he sleep every weekend?",b:" Does he wash every week days?",c:" Does he travel every month?",d:"Does he travel every day?"},section:"choose the option that best answers the question from the options lettered A-D",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Option c is the correct answer because WEEKEND contradicts the phrase 'every month'",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2021",questionNub:60,hasPassage:0,category:"others"}],s={subject:e,status:200,total:40,data:t};export{t as data,s as default,o as status,e as subject,a as total};
